# Ms Janet DORNAN, MIET, BEng Warwickshire, CV37 7AH

Email: j.dornan@physics.org Mobile: 07890 284497 Website: https://janet-dev.github.io

**LinkedIn**: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/janetdornan/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/janetdornan/</a> GitHub: @janet-dev

I am a front-end web developer and ex-industrial UI engineer with over ten years' experience in the control industry. Due to my interest in solving technical problems, I am now expanding my knowledge of information technology in order gain a coveted role in the world of web development.

I am highly motivated with excellent research skills, which enabled the building of a product-based website using self-hosted WordPress and marketing via social media sites. I have excellent administration skills, through the use of Microsoft Office, Open Office and Libre Office, as well as proficiency in using Windows, OS X and Linux. After completing a PGCert in Software and Systems Security and an eight week course in Web Development with Code First Girls, I am now fully committed to expanding my knowledge by updating my UI skills for the technology market. In the meantime, I am studying React at Udemy as well as enrolling on an UI/UX course with Figma.

I am very much a team player, but also comfortable with working alone. Skilled at multitasking, managing time effectively and prioritising tasks in line with the business. Excellent at communication, both verbally and written, as well as confident with social media platforms. Able to team manage and facilitate department meetings. Possess advanced customer service skills in dealing with the public or business clients. Well versed in mentoring both customers and clients on new departmental standards.

I would now like to utilise these skills, as well as the experience gained from my years in the control industry, and undertake new challenges in technology.

# **Career Professional Development**

- CodeFirstGirls.org.uk: Introduction to Web Development 06 Oct 24 Nov 2020 (remote with everis.co.uk)
- Forage.com (formerly InsideSherpa.com) Virtual Internship Participant with the

Commonwealth Bank's Careers in Tech (July - Sept 2020):

Design (UX/UI), Software Engineering, Cyber Security, Data Science and Analytics, AI / Robotics

Udemy.com online courses:

2020 Complete Web Development Bootcamp [current]

React – The Complete Guide [current]

Learn Figma – User Interface Design Essentials [future]

- Codebar.io student member
- WildCodeSchool.com Prep Courses (10 hours each) completed: Data Analyst. Web Developer
- Magazine subscription of Linux Format
- Medium.com online paid subscription (includes publishing written content)

## Office Skills

- Microsoft Office (Microsoft Excel, Access, Word, PowerPoint), Open Office, Libre Office
- Graphics / HMI (Human Machine Interface) / UI design packages used within the control system industry
- Windows, OS X and Linux operating systems (Ubuntu/Mint)
- WordPress.org for self hosted website building
- Social media for marketing Instagram, Facebook, Pinterest, TikTok, YouTube
- Canva for marketing and branding
- Manual data analysis within a small bakery
- Domain knowledge of the oil and gas industry, control engineering, food and fashion retail, hospitality, catering and event security

## **Employment History**

09/2019 – Present	Baker / Food Assistant	Spar
08/2017 – 09/2019	Customer Host / Stockroom Operator	White Stuff
07/2017 – 08/2017	Barista	Coffee#1
09/2016 – 07/2017	Door Supervisor/Guard/Steward	AES / TKD Security / Spears Worldwide
01/2016 - 04/2016	Field Services Engineer	Schneider Electric (Invensys)
04/2015 – 10/2018	University of Oxford	Software Engineering Programme Student
01/2012 – 10/2014	Field Services Engineer	Invensys Systems Nigeria
02/2010 – 01/2012	Waitress	Le Bistrot Pierre
01/2009 – 01/2010	Graphics Engineer	Honeywell Process Systems
08/2002 – 12/2008	Applications Engineer	GroupCytek
05/2000 - 05/2006	Signaller	Army Reserves

## **Education:**

University of Oxford - PGCert in Software and Systems Security - PGCE Secondary Physics and Science University of Birmingham - BEng(Hons) in Electronic and Electrical Engineering RGIT (RGU), Aberdeen Strathearn School, Belfast

- A Level: Physics, Biology; NIGCE: Maths - B, English - B, French

Languages: - GCSE Russian - A, German as a Foreign Language

**Professional Memberships:** - Member of the Institution of Engineering and Technology

- Member of the Institute of Physics

Interests: - Designing and marketing own handmade artisan jewellery

- Keen allotment owner growing vegetables and tortoise food